<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <info>
        <title>JPAContainer Manual</title>
        <author>
            <personname>
                <firstname>Petter</firstname>
                <surname>Holmström</surname>
            </personname>
            <email>petter.holmstrom@itmill.com</email>
        </author>
        <copyright>
            <year>2009, 2010</year>
            <holder>Oy IT Mill Ltd.</holder>
        </copyright>
    </info>
    
    <section xml:id="introduction">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>
            JPAContainer is a <link xl:href="http://vaadin.com">Vaadin</link> data container that uses the Java Persistence API (JPA) for retrieving and storing data.
            It supports the most common features required by JEE applications out of the box, such as lazy loading, advanced filtering, nested property names and caching.
            It will probably not solve all the container problems you as a JEE application developers might face, but it will hopefully make your life a little easier.
        </para>
        <para>
            The purpose of this manual is to briefly explain how JPAContainer works and how you can use it in your applications. TODO Continue...
        </para>
        <note>
            <title>Work in progress</title>
            <para>
                This manual is a work in progress. Many sections have been described very shallowly, more depth will be added later. If you think something is missing,
                please let me now ASAP!
            </para>
        </note>
        <section>
            <title>Architecture</title>
            <para>
                The architecture of JPAContainer consists of two main components: an <classname>EntityContainer</classname> and an <classname>EntityProvider</classname>:
            </para>

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata align="center" fileref="provider.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>

            <para>
                The <classname>EntityContainer</classname> is an extended version of the standard Vaadin container and can be used directly to power e.g. tables or combo boxes.
                The container gets its data from an <classname>EntityProvider</classname>, which in turn loads the data from some data source. It is possible to have several
                containers using the same provider, making it possible to e.g. add a second-level cache to the provider. It is even possible to deploy the containers and the provider
                to different JVMs:
            </para>

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata align="center" fileref="distributed.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>

            <para>
                Most of the public API of JPAContainer is defined in interfaces. The following diagram displays the most important classes and interfaces, and their relations. The gray
                interfaces are part of the official Vaadin API
            </para>

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata align="center" fileref="interfaces.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>

            <para>
                The <classname>JPAContainer</classname> class is the default implementation of the <classname>EntityContainer</classname> interface. TODO Continue...
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section xml.id="using">
        <title>Using JPAContainer in Applications</title>
        <para>
            Write about how to use JPAContainer in applications
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml.id="demo">
        <title>The Hitchhiker's Guide to The Demo Application</title>
        <para>
            Write about the demo application
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml.id="custom-entity-providers">
        <title>Developing Custom Entity Providers</title>
        <para>
            Write about developing custom entity providers
        </para>
    </section>
</article>
